<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><ttl>60</ttl><title>ASO News</title><description>ASO Savings &amp; Loans Plc News</description><link>http://www.asoplc.com/pages/media/index.php#news26</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 13:33:14 GMT</pubDate><category></category><image/><skipDays/><skipHours/><generator>Advanced RSS Publisher</generator><item><title>MD of ASO Savings &amp; Loans PLC Advocates Incentives For PMIs</title><description>The MD of ASO Savings &amp; Loans PLC Mr. Hassan Usman has stated that although the Nigerian economy has grown from $46BN to $247bn in the last ten years, considerable impact is still yet to be made to improve housing delivery in the country. He made this known at a conference on Shelter and Urban Renewal, held recently to commemorate the World Habitat Day.

According to him, less than 30,000 housing units are developed every year as against the annual demand of between 500,000 to 1,000,000 by Nigerians. He added that the absence of viable quality mass housing developers and the reluctance of Banks to fund residential real estate among other factors, contributes largely to this challenge.

Enumerating on incentives that are needed to boost the Housing Sector, Mr. Hassan said access to inexpensive lands, 5 year Tax holiday for Mass Housing developers, Mortgage Interest Relief and the creation of a N250BN origination fund will go a long way. He advocated that allowing PMIs access to CBN discount window and the foreign exchange market would encourage better mortgage creation. Added to this, allowing investments by PMIs and Banks in mortgage assets and mortgage backed securities to count as part of their liquidity reserve requirements whilst allowing recapitalized PMIs to go to clearing House were noted by the MD as potential spurs to further the provision of mortgages.

Mr. Hassan concluded that to reduce the current Housing crisis in Nigeria, a critical intervention is required to increase Housing Finance from 1% to 5% of GDP within the next 5 years.</description><link>http://www.asoplc.com/pages/media/#news32</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 13:34:54 GMT</pubDate><source></source><category></category><guid></guid><enclosure length="0" type="application/dvcs"/></item><item><title>ASO sponsors Emir of Kano Golf Tournament
</title><description>As part of efforts aimed at promoting and supporting the game of golf in Nigeria, ASO Savings &amp; Loans Plc in collaboration with the Nigeria Professional Golf Association sponsored the Third Emir of Kano Golf tournament, held at the Kano Golf Club.

The six-day tournament which featured two cadres – professional and amateur, attracted some of the best golfers from across the nation.

The management of the bank was represented by the Executive Director Operations &amp; Technology, Shehu Inuwa Mohammed. Speaking at the closing ceremony, Mr. Mohammed said ASO was desirous of supporting the growth of golf in the country, in view of the ever-rising popularity of the game globally, of which he said Nigeria must not be left out.

The event was graced by the Executive Governor of Kano, Dr Rabiu Musa Kwankwaso, and the Turakin Kano, Alhaji Nasir Ado Bayero, who represented the Emir. Prizes were given to deserving winners at the end of the tournament.</description><link>http://www.asoplc.com/pages/media/#news31</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 13:41:57 GMT</pubDate><source></source><category></category><guid></guid><enclosure length="0" type="application/dvcs"/></item></channel></rss>
